JU YOUNG KIM

Phone: +821076460746 Email: juyoung.kim517@gmail.com LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/ju-young-kim-048215b6 GitHub Resume: https://juyoungkimthedev.github.io/resume

Summary

I have 5 years of software engineering experience mostly in fast-paced and agile startup companies with focus in fintech ranging from banking and insurance to payments. I have lots of hands-on experience building RESTful web services and ETL data pipeline for machine learning platforms. I have strong teamwork spirit and ethics and I plan to use these skills together with clean and efficient coding strategies to improve company processes and provide most optimal solutions for clients.

Experience

Primer | Backend Software Engineer | London, United Kingdom

February 2022 - Present

- As part of the core framework team, implemented and maintained Starlette based application framework to enable building of internal and third-party apps. Led migration of old apps to the new framework.
- Maintained and improved an existing FastAPI based core API by adding new endpoints, handlers and controllers that allow interservice interactions. Tools used: Aiohttp, SQLAlchemy, Kafka.
- Created codebase for marketplace API service that connects to the core API to serve app instances and specifications to merchants, allowing complete app management on the dashboard.
- Reduced time to build and maintain apps by 80% by creating an automation tool to manage app creation and metadata updates, eliminating frequent data migrations and manual assets upload to S3.

Root | Software Engineer | Cape Town, South Africa

April 2021 – January 2022

- Joined product team to build features for the core insurance platform. Worked mostly on server side TypeScript/Node.js code as well as some frontend components using React.js.
- Implemented policy document encryption functionality using Node.js qpdf wrapper to automatically password protect policy related documents before sending to clients.
- Ported user product module code execution environment from Node.js vm2 to AWS Lambda functions to allow for more secure code execution and dependency management.
- Improved the legacy React codebase by refactoring to the new internal web architecture. Mostly worked on changing class component code to functional component with React hooks.

Praelexis | Software Engineer & Data Engineer | Cape Town, South Africa

March 2018 - March 2021

- Designed and implemented backend apps serving credit machine learning models for a large retail South African bank using Python, Flask and Docker.
- Created and deployed large-scale data engineering and machine learning workflows to serve data for credit apps using Luigi, Airflow, PySpark and Databricks.
- Contributed to migrating core data lake services built on top of Azure to AWS using EMR, Glue, Athena.

Education

- University of Cape Town: Master of Science: Bioinformatics, 2018
- University of Pretoria: Bachelor of Science Honors in Bioinformatics, 2014
- University of Pretoria: **Bachelor of Science** in Biochemistry, 2013

Technical Skills

- Languages: Python, JavaScript, TypeScript, Julia, R, Go, Java
- Frameworks and Libraries: FastAPI, Flask, Aiohttp, SQLAlchemy, Node.js, Express.js, React.js,
- Database: PostgreSQL, CosmosDB, DynamoDB
- Cloud and DevOps: AWS (S3, Lambda, ECR), Azure (Blobstore, AKS), Docker, Kubernetes, Helm, Terraform, Heroku
- Data: Databricks, PySpark, Apache Kafka
- Tools: Git, GitLab, Pipeline CI/CD, BitBucket, JIRA, Localstack, VS Code, Postman, PyCharm, Datadog, Feature flags